Guide to the Erroll Garner Archive, 1942-2010 AIS.2015.09 AIS.2015.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Martha Glaser Papers, 1921-2010; VIII.
  - Education, 1932-1941; 10.
    - Wayne State University Notes, 1939-1941 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Wayne State University Notes (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Wayne State University Notes (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Wayne State University Notes (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Wayne State University Notes (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Wayne State University Notes (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Wayne State University Commencement Certificate, 1942 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Student Defense Committee (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - The Detroit Collegian, 1940-1942 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Race Relations, 1943-1946; 11.
    The Race Relations subseries contains material on the fight for race equality in Chicago, Detroit, and in entertainment.
    - Chicago, 1945-1946 (Box 78, Folder 7-10)
      - Race Relations in Chicago, 1945-1946
        Scope and Contents
        This item includes; Analysis of Chicago School Strikes created by American Council on Race Relations, Chicago Il. 1945, papers related to Martha Glaser's time as Assistant in the Department of Public Information and Education, and documents related to a report titled The Mayor's Commission on Human Relations from 1945 to 1946.
      - Race Relations in Chicago, 1945-1946
      - Race Relations in Chicago, 1945-1946
        This item includes the Report of the Mayor's Committee on Race Relations in Chicago for the year 1944, a document titled "Mayor's Committee on Race Relations Financial Statement 1944", a document titled "Chicago Charter of Human Relations adopted by Chicago Conference on Home Front Unity 1945", the Report of the Mayor's Commission on Human Relations for 1945, and a document titled "Police Training Bulletin: A Guide to Race Relations for Police Officers."
      - Race Relations in Chicago, 1945-1946
        This item includes the following documents; "Human Relations in Chicago: Reports of Commissions and Charter of Human Relations 1945," a pamphlet for Chicago Conference on Home Front Unity 1945, a pamphlet for "The National Negro Museum and Historical Foundation" dated 1945, proceedings from the Chicago Conference on Home Front Unity 1945, a pamphlet titled "Negro Soldiers in American Wars" published in 1944, "Charter for Human Relations: A Dumbarton Oaks for Chicago" adopted 1945 by Chicago Conference on Home Front Unity, a pamphlet of Chicago Conference on Home Front Unity for Fall meeting 1945, and "Race Relations in Chicago" a Report of the Mayor's Commission on Human Relations for 1945.
    - Race Relations in Detroit, 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      This item includes a pamphlet titled "Design for Living in a Democratic World: Fifth Annual Conference of the League of Detroit Jewish Youth 1944," and several correspondences from the Metropolitan Detroit Youth Council to various individuals regarding demonstrations in Detroit during 1943.
    - Race Dialogue (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Articles about Race in Jazz (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Race connected to Music (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, c. 1921-2010; 12.
    The Photographs subseries contains photos of Martha, Erroll, and the Farkas family, starting from the early 1900s to 2010.
    - Farkas Family Hungarian, c.1900-1950 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Martha's Parents Sam and Peral Farkas, c. 1930-1950 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Peral Farkas (Martha's Mother), c.1915-1955 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Sam Farkas (Martha's Father), c. 1915-1960 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Farkas Family Soliders, c. 1940-1945 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Farkas Family Children (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Martha Early Years, c. 1921-1975 (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
    - Martha Later Years, c.1976-2010 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Susan Rosenberg, c. 1956-1980 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Bella Rosenberg, c. 1921-1980 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Martha and Erroll (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Frakas Family Single (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Frakas Family Group (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - New York City, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Portraits (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Portraits (Box 80, Folder 1-2)
    - Photomatic, c. 1940 (Box 80, Folder 3-4)
    - Negatives (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Legal [RESTRICTED], 1921-2007; 14.
    The Legal subseries contains Glaser birth certificate, last will and testament, and power of attorney. Access to it is currently RESTRICTED.
    - Birth Certificate, 1921 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Social Security Card (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Marraige and Divorce Records, 1939-1947 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Passports, 1967-1996 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Last Will and Testament, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Power of Attorney, 1996 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Condo Rights, 2007 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Deposition, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Deposition, 1992 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Martha Lawsuit vs. Lehrer-McGovern (scaffold accident), 1957, 1989-1998 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Martha Lawsuit vs. Lehrer-McGovern (scaffold accident), 1989-1998 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - Martha Lawsuit vs. Lehrer-McGovern (scaffold accident), 1989-1998 (Box 80, Folder 17)
    - Martha Lawsuit vs. Lehrer-McGovern (scaffold accident), 1989-1998 (Box 80, Folder 18)
  - Realia, c.1921-1970; 13.
    The Realia subseries contains jewelry and desk items from Glaser.
    - Earrings (Box 81, Item 1)
    - Diamond Earring (Box 81, Item 2)
    - Makeup Case (Box 81, Item 3)
    - Cubic Zirconia Earring (Box 81, Item 4)
    - Cubic Zirconia Ball Earring (Box 81, Item 5)
    - Pattern Earring (Box 81, Item 6)
    - Pearl Ring (Box 81, Item 7)
    - Lose Cubic Zirconia (Box 81, Item 8)
    - Paper Weight (Box 81, Item 9)
    - Pins (Box 81, Item 10-12)
    - Rosary Beads (Box 81, Item 13)
    - Pink Cubic Zirconia Earring (Box 81, Item 14)
    - Watch (Box 81, Item 15)
    - Buttons (Box 81, Item 16)
    - Tie Clips (Box 81, Item 17)